Earlier in this lesson, you saw how violin and box plots could be used to
之前 本课介绍了如何用小提琴图和箱线图
depict the relationship between one quantitative and one qualitative variable.
来描绘数值变量和分类变量之间的关系
In this video, we'll use an alternative strategy faceting
现在我们要用另一种替代方法
histograms of the quantitative variable against the qualitative subsets of the data.
根据分类变量拆分数据 从而对数值变量的直方图进行分面处理
To perform faceting, we're going to make use of Seaborn's Facet Grid Object Class.
要完成分面 我们使用 seaborn 的 FacetGrid 类对象
I'm going to set two parameters for creating the facet grid object.
我要设置两个参数来创建 FacetGrid 对象
The fuel_econ data frame is assigned to data like before,
一个是 data 像之前一样将 fuel_econ DataFrame 赋给该参数
and then we assign VClass column to the col parameter.
另一个是 col 将列名 Vclass 赋给该参数
What this means that for whatever plot we facet with,
这样一来 无论我们要分面什么图表
there will be one of that plot made for each level of vehicle class.
图表都会按汽车类型拆分成若干子图
Now, we need to say what kind of plot we want to generate for each of
接着 指明各分面要生成的图表种类
the facets using the map function of facet grid objects.
为此 使用对象 FacetGrid 的函数 map
The first argument is the plotting function.
第一个参数是绘图函数
In this case hist.
即直方图 hist
The following argument is the variable to be plotted on the x axis.
第二个参数是要绘制的 x 轴变量名
In this case comb.
也就是 comb
It's important that you don't set x equals in this,
注意 不要设 x = comb
or the faceting by subgroups won't work correctly.
否则分面无法正确分组
You can see that all of the data is plotted using the default ten bins for
你可以看到 所有数据都按函数 hist 默认的分为十组
the hist function but the axis limits are the same for each facet.
但每个分面的坐标轴范围是一样的
This is useful for comparing the frequency of each group on
这有利于比较分面变量各组的频率
the faceted variable and the values within each group for the plotted variable.
与绘制变量各组的值
Let's do a little tweaking to the plots.
我们来做些调整
First, I'll add a bins parameter to the map function,
首先 在函数 map 里添加参数 bins
so that the bins across each facet are the same.
使各分面的组相同
Next, I'll add the col_wrap parameter
接着 添加参数 col_wrap
to limit the number of facets that can be placed side by side.
限制并排放置的分面数
This isn't vital for this particular data set but it can be
虽然这个数据集不要求这一步操作
useful if you have a lot more levels in your faceted variable.
但如果要分面的变量类别很多 这一步就很实用了
Lastly, I want to demonstrate what happens if you
最后 我想说一下
don't fix the same axis limits across facets.
如果你不想固定各分面的轴范围 要怎么做
By setting share y equals false in the facet grid col,
在调用对象 FacetGrid 中设 sharey = False
each facet can have its own y axis limits.
每个分面就能有自己的 y 轴范围了
It's a little easier this way to see the change in distributions across levels,
这样更方便你观察各类别的分布差异
but you also lose out on seeing the overall frequency of each group.
但也就无法比较各组的总频率了
If you're not paying attention,
一不小心
you might think that each class has a similar number of
你会以为各类别的车辆数量差不多
cars when in fact they're not exactly the same
而事实可能并非如此